停下
Hold it.
搞什么
What the...
谁去喊工头
Hey! Somebody call the foreman!
早饭  分头击破吗
So, breakfast... divide and conquer?
我去煮咖啡
I'll make the coffee.
我去做鸡蛋饼
I'll make the omelettes.
我要让你们开心一整天
And I am going to make your day.
我带来了激动人心的好消息
I have the most exciting news.
我只是想等你们干完
I just wanted to wait until you were finished doing,
-你们在里面干的事  -睡觉吗
- you know, whatever you were doing in there. - Sleeping?
什么消息
Uh, what news?
关于你们的婚礼
About your wedding.
你想到花卉摆放的办法了
Um, you've come up with options for flower arrangements.
我费尽心思
I have searched high and low
想要抓住你们的精髓
trying to capture the look that is the essence of you.
我呈现
I give you...
爱之通道
The tunnel of love.
新郎新娘走向圣坛
The bride and groom walk to the altar
走过用外域鲜花装饰的通道
through the arched passageway festooned with exotic flowers.
然后我又找到了这个
Then I found this.
那是一张大照片吗
Is that a giant photograph?
而且完全是花垒砌成的
Made entirely of flowers?
没错  不过  当然会做成是你们的样子
Yes, except it would be, of course, the two of you,
由技艺高超的艺术家精心打造
Painstakingly crafted by skilled artisans. Just
-还有呢  -妈妈
- But wait, there's more. - Mother.
我虽然很感激你如此投入
As much as I appreciate your passion,
而且显然做足了功课
and obviously, diligent research,
我只是觉得这有点过了
I just think this is...A little too much.
是指开销吗
In terms of expense?
应该说是
In terms of...
各方面
E-everything.
理查德  你为什么对我的主意都不屑一顾呢
Richard, why do you just dismiss all of my ideas about your ceremony?
你是说用妮基·希特的冰雕做装饰
You mean like your ideas of bringing in giant ice sculptures
雇佣维也纳童声合唱团
of Nikki Heat or hiring the Vienna boys' choir
让蓝色天使从头顶飞过吗
or having the blue angels fly overhead?
理查德  我只是想
Richard, I'm simply trying to bring
让你的婚礼更华丽些
a little pageantry into your wedding. But...
看来你们只想让我做来宾
Seems the only role you want me to play is that of guest.
好啊  没问题
Fine. I can do that.
我只是让她看看花卉  别弄得太铺张
I just asked her to check into flowers and keep it simple.
就凭她的过去  我该想到的
With her track record, I-I s-should've known better.
她没有恶意  卡塞尔
Look, she means well, Castle.
她只是想参与进来
She just wants to be a part of this,
我们找点别的让她做吧
so let's find something for her to do...
给她个婚礼项目
Some kind of a...wedding project.
你说得对
Yes. You're right,
但得找个不会被她弄得一团糟的
but something she can't turn into an over-the-top disaster.
-我再想想  -我也是
- I'll keep thinking. - Yeah, me too.
这栋大楼本该进行爆破了
Yo. So, this building was set to be demolished.
可是进行拆卸作业的工程队
That is, until the salvage crew stripping the place
发现了这具尸体
came across this body.
还是埋在水泥里
Buried under concrete, no less.
死因知道了吗
You got a cause of death?
我得先做全面尸检  但他可能
Not till I do a full exam, but he's probably been here
1978年浇筑水泥的时候就在里面了
since they poured the concrete back in 1978.
卡特总统时期的死尸
A dead man from the Carter administration
还被埋在水泥里  太有意思了
entombed in cement... I am intrigued.
还知道死者的什么情况吗
Anything else you can tell us about the victim?
他大概三十出头  衣着不俗
He was maybe early 30s, and a sharp dresser.
看他的浅灰蓝西装
Check out that powder-blue suit.
是啊  迪斯科时代的装束
Yeah, straight from the disco era.
并且也证实了聚酯材料真的是不可摧毁
And a testament to the truly indestructible nature of polyester.
我们去查查78年时大厦是谁的
We'll check out who owned the building back in '78
-现在是谁的  -再查查许可证
- and who owns it now. - We'll also pull permits,
看看能不能查到注水泥的是谁
see if we can track down who poured this concrete.
我知道他是谁了
I know who the victim is.
什么
What?
30来岁的男人
A man in his 30s,
喜欢尾戒和沛纳海手表
with a penchant for pinkie rings and Panerai watches...
1978年神秘消失  拜托啊
Who mysteriously vanished in 1978. Come on!
文森·比安奇吗
Vince Bianchi?
比安奇犯罪家族的首领
Head of the Bianchi crime family?
而且是当年最有权势  最受人畏惧的黑帮头目
And one of the most powerful and feared mafia dons of his day,
直到他像吉米·霍法一样神秘消失
until he disappeared Jimmy Hoffa style.
这三十多年来  他一直在这儿
And for over three decades, he was right here.
我们刚刚找到了文森·比安奇
We just found Vince Bianchi.
文森·比安奇
Vince Bianchi,
在他变成你们找到的那堆白骨之前
before he turned into the pile of bones you guys found.
当时  我们努力想把他抓进监狱
Back then, we were trying to take him off the streets.
然后1978年7月30日  有人替我们除掉了他
Then on July 30, 1978, somebody did it for us.
这么大的案子
High-profile case like this,
盖茨却偏偏这时候去参加恐怖主义讨论会
Gates sure did pick the wrong week to go to a terrorism seminar.
博伊尔警探
Detective Boyle,
会不会是别的犯罪家族杀了他
could one of the other crime families have had him killed?
这绝对有可能
It's definitely possible.
刀锋迈奇·卡卡诺
"Mickey the Blade" Carcano,
利嘴路易·马奈利
Louie "The lip" Maneri.
都想在比安奇的地盘上插一脚
Both wanted to muscle in on Bianchi's territory,
所以他们有动机
so they had motive.
简直像是穿越去了过去
It's like being transported to a bygone era.
刀锋迈奇  利嘴路易
Mickey the blade. Louie the lip.
这些人现在都在哪啊
Where are these guys now?
可能都在水泥里呢
Probably under concrete.
文森在比安奇家族内也有敌人
Vince also had rivals inside the Bianchi family.
这些人有嫌疑吗
Were any of these rivals suspects?
有  这人
Yeah, this guy.
弗兰克·鲁索  他的副手之一
Frank Russo, one of his lieutenants.
文森失踪后  他接管了比安奇家族
He took over the Bianchi family after Vince vanished
而且他是最后见到他的人之一
and was one of the last people to see him alive.
他们那晚在吉诺餐馆一起吃过饭
They had dinner together that night at Gino's restaurant.
店主给弗兰克和文森照了这张相
The owner snapped this picture of Frank and Vince...
这是文森·比安奇的最后一张照片
The last known photo of Vince Bianchi.
弗兰克称他开车送文森回了家  再就没见到他
Frank claimed he drove Vince home and never saw him again.
你觉得究竟是怎么回事
What do you think really happened?
我觉得弗兰克劝服文森跟他去城里玩一晚
I think Frank talked Vince into a night on the town,
把他引去了什么地方  杀了他
lured him someplace, and killed him.
但我们始终没能证明
But we could never prove it.
卡塞尔  你看文森在餐馆穿的那套西服
Castle, look at the suit that Vince was wearing at the restaurant.
是黑色的  不是浅灰蓝的
It's black. It's not powder blue.
那么说他当晚吃完饭的确去了别处
So, he did go out after dinner that night.
所以弗兰克·鲁索撒谎了
And Frank Russo was lying.
我们得跟弗兰克·鲁索谈谈
We need to talk to Frank Russo.
文森是个好人  安息吧
Vince was a good man. God rest.
至少现在能好好埋葬他了
Now at least he'll get a proper burial.
鲁索先生
Yeah, Mr. Russo,
我们想再问问他失踪那晚的事
we'd like to revisit the night that he disappeared.
那件事都是很多年前了
Look, that whole thing was ages ago.
是的  在那之后
Right, and after it happened,
你接管了比安奇犯罪家族  对吗
you took over the Bianchi crime family. Isn't that true?
现在我都做合法生意了
I'm legit now. I own several businesses.
一点没错
Oh, yeah.
就是把你扫地出门的人不要的小生意罢了
Crumbs the family threw you when they shoved you out the door.
你住的这4000平方英尺的屋子
Hey, excuse me for making an honest living
可是这些正经小生意赚来的
to keep 4,000 square feet over your head!
又不是什么阁楼公寓  对吧弗兰克
Yeah, but it's not the penthouse, is it, Frank?
不是顶层哦
It's not the top floor.
你们想干什么
What are you gonna do?
请你告诉我们
You know, why don't you just walk us through
那晚在吉诺餐馆到底发生了什么
what happened at Gino's restaurant?
我和文森吃饭闲聊
Vince and I broke bread, we shot the breeze.
文森谈到了未来  说要安定下来
Vince talked about the future, settling down,
说黑帮头目一定要重视家庭
how important it was for a don to be a family man.
晚餐后  我把他送回了家  就这样
After dinner, I dropped him home. That was it.
那之后你再没和文森一起出去
And you and Vince didn't go out afterwards?
又来了  我得回答多少次才行  没有
Again with this? How many times do I got to say it? No.
那么他死时穿的衣服为什么
Then why was he found in a different suit
和在吉诺餐馆穿的不一样
than the one that he wore at Gino's restaurant?
我不知道
I have no idea.
就算他是出了门  我也不知道
If he went out after, it's news to me.
不过如果他真的出去了
But if he did go out,
哈罗德肯定会知道
Harold would've known about it.
哈罗德是谁
Harold?
哈罗德·利昂
Harold Leone.
文森芝麻大的事都会告诉哈罗德
Vince didn't brush his teeth without talking to Harold.
我说弗兰克只是随便给出个名字
If you ask me, Frank's just pointing at something shiny
来转移注意力
so you quit looking at him.
很有可能
Yeah, well, that's very possible,
不过哈罗德·利昂是谁
But who is Harold Leone?
文森的军师  参谋
Vince's advisor, his consigliere.
就像教父里的汤姆·哈根
Like Tom Hagen in "The Godfather."
可是文森失踪后
Yeah, but after Vince went missing,
哈罗德就不怎么出来了
Harold kind of dropped off the world.
-他当时是嫌疑人吗  -不是
- Was he ever a suspect? - No.
但是流言说他知道内幕
But word was he knew things.
他现在在哪
So, where can we find him now?
我应该有他的住址
I might have an address in my files.
打扰一下  夫人
Excuse me, ma'am.
-你好  -纽约警察
- Hi. - NYPD.
我们来找哈罗德·利昂
We're looking for Harold Leone.
他住这里对吗
Is this where he lives?
我是伊凡  哈罗德的保姆
Uh, I'm Yvonne. I look after Harold.
我们想和他聊聊
Well, we'd like to speak with him.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
他内心深处是个好人
I mean, he's a sweet man deep down,
只是有点不正常
but he's just a little off.
怎么个不正常法
Off how?
他们管那叫悲伤过度
Pathological grieving is what they call it.
哈罗德最好的朋友78年失踪了
Harold's best friend disappeared back in '78,
哈罗德再也没有恢复过来
and Harold, he never got over it.
他的生活停滞不前了
Never moved on.
就像被冰封在了过去
It's like he's frozen in time.
所以他整天闷在屋子里  留着这车
That's why he stays home and still owns this car
而且还让我穿这些傻衣服
and makes me wear these dumbass clothes.
抱歉  你是说哈罗德以为
I'm sorry, are you saying that Harold thinks
现在还是70年代吗
it's the 1970s?
没错
Yeah.
而且任何戳穿这个假象的事实
And anything that happens that bursts that bubble,
都会让他陷入混乱
oh, he just gets all confused.
所以你们进去和他说话时
So, when you go in to talk to him,
得把手机关了
just turn off your cellphones,
假装回到了40年前
pretend like it's 40 years ago.
其余的就没问题了
You shouldn't have any problem.
不过你可能会有点麻烦
Actually, you will have a problem.
伊迪丝  我回来啦
Edith, I'm home!
你好  阿奇
Oh, hello, Archie!
瞧瞧啊
Look at this place.
哈罗德
Harold?!
有客人
You have guests!
这个辣妹愿意整晚待这儿都行
Well, this hot mama could be my guest all night long.
先生  我是贝克特探长
Uh, sir, I'm detective Beckett,
这位是卡塞尔先生
and this is Mr. Castle.
-队长  -卡塞尔
- Captain. - Castle.
卡塞尔队长
Well, captain Castle,
我猜这位小姐是刚来的吧
I bet you're, uh, showing this little lady the ropes, huh?
还在调训中对吧
Breaking her in, huh?
事实上
Well, actually, um --
你见过这么漂亮的美女当警察的吗
I mean, have you ever seen a cop with an ass that fine?
这就是妇女解放运动吗  那我全力支持
If this is women's lib, I'm all for it.
什么
Excuse me?
说实话  你确实...当我没说
To be fair, you do have a very fine -- never mind.
需要我做什么  队长
So, how can I help you, captain?
事实上  我们是为文森·比安奇而来
Uh, well, truth is, we are here about Vince Bianchi.
你们找到他了
You found him?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid we did.
他死时身穿一件浅蓝色西服
He was found in a light-blue suit.
我们认为他被杀当晚
We believe he went somewhere
从吉诺餐馆回来后又去了别的地方
after he left Gino's restaurant the night that he was killed.
有人说他做什么事都会告诉你
Now, we were told he kept you informed about what he did.
你知道他那晚去了哪里吗
You have any idea where he went that night?
知道
Yeah.
我也知道是谁杀了他
And I know who killed him, too.
确认一下
Just to be clear,
你是说你知道杀掉文森·比安奇的凶手
you're saying you know who killed Vince Bianchi?
他叫什么名字
What's his name?
这个问题太危险了  宝贝
That's a dangerous question, sweetheart.
我需要保护
I'm gonna need protection.
必要的话我可以调警员来保护你
I can assign officers to protect you if necessary.
必要的话
"If necessary"?
能麻烦你告诉这个小甜心
Will you tell cupcake here
我和你们说话都是冒着生命危险吗
that -- that I'm risking my life just talking to you guys?
杀了文森的人随时可能来取我的性命
The people that killed Vince will do the same to me in a heartbeat.
我觉得真的不太可能
I-I think that's really unlikely.
大多数人都不在了
I mean, most of those people aren't even around
都这么多年了  所以
after all these years, so --
什么这么多年了
What do you mean "Years"?
文森  失踪很多年了吗  不
Vince... has not been gone for -- for years. No.
我想贝克特警探的意思是
I'm sure what detective Beckett meant to say --
这是个骗局
This is a trick.
你是为了套我的话
You are trying to trick me into saying things.
或许文森根本没死
Maybe Vince isn't even dead.
他确实死了
No, he most definitely is.
那就给我看看
Well, then show me.
要我告诉你是谁杀了他
If I'm gonna tell you who killed him,
就得先让我见到尸体
I need to see his face first.
抱歉  哈罗德  这恐怕不可能
I'm sorry, Harold, but that's impossible.
为什么
Why?
你说他死了  那就让我见到尸体
If Vince is dead, show me his body!
-哈罗德  -没见到尸体我什么也不说
- Harold -- - No body, no talkie.
先生
Sir.
我以纽约警察赋予我的权力向您保证
By the power vested in me by the NYPD,
我会亲自安排你去探视死者
I will personally arrange for you to view the deceased.
你是一个讲信用的人  队长
You are a man of honor, captain.
能出来谈谈吗  队长
Can we speak outside... captain?
当然
Of course.
新手嘛
Rookies.
"赋予我的权力"
"By the power vested in me"?
卡塞尔  你在干什么
Castle, what the hell were you doing?
是你说漏了嘴
I was trying to stop the meltdown he had
我只是不想让他崩溃
when you steped out of the '70s.
就答应让他看根本就没有的尸体
By promising him a body that we don't have.
他能帮我们解决著名的黑帮残杀的案子
He can help us solve an infamous gangland slaying.
或许他是在幻想
Maybe he's delusional.
我们都知道他弄不清楚年代
We already know he's delusional about what year it is.
要得到他知道的消息  得让他相信我们
If we're gonna find out what he knows, he has to trust us.
他得先看到一具尸体
He needs to see a body.
蕾妮在停尸房找到线索了
Lanie's got something at the morgue.
你知道她还有什么吗  尸体
You know what else she's got? Bodies.
很多的尸体
Lots of them.
可能有一具看上去够像文森·比安奇
Maybe one of them looks enough like Vince Bianchi.
想都别想  小甜心
Don't even go there, cupcake.
你就是这么查那栋楼的主人的
This you checking out who owns that building?
我在等档案组的电话
I'm waiting on a call from records.
所以我顺便了解一下那个年代的东西
So I figured I'd study up on the period,
就从这个
by starting...
我找到的纪录片开始
with this documentary I found
关于当时两个彪悍的纽约警局警探
on these two NYPD badasses from back in the day.
斯努基·沃兹还有雷·普莱斯
Snookie Watts, Ray Price.
快看斯努基这一段的动作
Check out Snookie's move right here.
斯努基  你和雷
Snookie, you and Ray
在打击罪案小组可是名声大噪
have made quite a name for yourselves in the anti-crime unit.
就是这样的  宝贝
Better believe it, baby.
打击犯罪一打一个准
Stopping crime one skell at a time.
没错  没错
Right on, right on.
坏人看到飞驰的红色跑车
See, when the bad guys see the ol' red rocket here,
就知道自己离死期不远了
they know a serious head cracking is on the way.
过去警察暴力的好日子
So, good ol' days of police brutality.
伙计  你不懂
Man, you just don't get it.
看上去我们的被害人是身中数枪而死
So, it looks like our victim was killed by multiple gunshot wounds.
我把他的头骨拼好时
When I pieced his skull back together,
我看到这个38口径手枪打出来的入口伤
I found this entry wound from a .38.
正中脑门
One in the noggin.
典型的黑帮杀人风格
Classic mafia rubout.
也不尽然
Not exactly.
据我观察
As near as I can figure,
他是先被射中了后背
Vince was shot in the back first,
可能他正准备离开
Maybe as he was walking away.
他的腹部有一个出口伤
There's an exit wound in his abdomen.
腹部  你光凭骨头就发现了这些
In his abdomen? You got all of that from bones?
我从这东西上获得了些帮助
I got a little help from this.
水泥在他身上凝结时
When the concrete settled on him,
就形成了一个非常棒的模子
it formed an almost perfect mold.
我们就做了一个他身体的模型
We were able to make a cast of the body
从模型上能看出出口伤
which showed the exit wound.
我们有尸体了
We have a body.
我们能让哈罗德看尸体了
We have a body to show Harold.
这就是让他开口的东西
This is exactly what we need to get him to talk.
卡塞尔  这是橡胶的
Castle. It's rubber!
他不需要知道这个
He doesn't need to know that.
找个熟练的入殓师
Couldn't a skilled mortician
给它弄点头发化个妆
apply a little hair and makeup to this,
让这看起来像是文森·比安奇行吗
make it look like a reasonable facsimile of vince bianchi?
我见过他们完成更困难的事
I've seen them do more with a lot less,
但我可不想掺和进来
but I don't want to be a part of some crazy plan --
你必须参与  为了让计划成功
Yeah, you have to, because for this to work,
这个地方得弄得像70年代  你也是
this place needs to look like the'70s, and so do you.
马奈利先生
So, Mr. Maneri,
既然文森·比安奇是死于谋杀
now that Vince Bianchi's death is officially a homicide,
我们必须盘查他之前所有的敌对者
we are re-interviewing all of his former enemies,
其中也包括你
including yourself.
你能不能告诉我们
Now, is it possible for you to tell me
1978年7月30日你在哪
where you were on July 30, 1978?
我可以代表我丈夫利嘴路易说
I speak for my husband, Louie the Lip here,
他没有参与干掉文森·比安奇
when I tell you that he had no part in whackin' Vince Bianchi.
即使他做了  他也不记得了
And even if he did, he doesn't remember.
就是她说的那样
What she said.
医生怎么跟你说的
What did the doctor tell you?
你要干嘛  让我变寡妇吗
What are you trying to do? Make me a widow?
你跟医生说过你不会再这么做了
You promised the doctor not to do that anymore.
你们俩能回避一下吗  谢谢
Could you two excuse me for a minute, please? Thanks.
这样你会早早进坟墓的
You're gonna put yourself in an early grave.
哥们  这个案子弄得我快没招了
Man, I'm spinning my wheels on this thing.
每个和案子有关的人要么死了
Everyone connected to this case is either dead
要么就像利嘴路易那样
or looks like Louie the Lip over there.
那个哈罗德可能是我们唯一的机会
This guy Harold might be our only shot at solving this thing.
什么  那个活在70年代的疯子
What, the kook who thinks it's the '70s?
不可能  兄弟  我找到一条线索
No way, bro. I just got us a real lead.
和那栋楼的主人有关吗
Connected to who owns the building?
差不多
Well, sort of.
原来在70年代
Turns out that back in the '70s,
黑帮插手了市内所有的建筑工程
the mob had a piece of all the concrete work in the city.
这些工程被划分给了不同的犯罪组织
It was divvied up so that different crime families
他们分管不同的区域
controlled different parts of town.
埋着文森的那块混凝土
Now, the concrete that Vince was found under
刚好处于卡卡诺家族的领地中心
was smack-dab in the middle of Carcano territory.
而卡卡诺家族是文森当时的头号劲敌
And the Carcanos were Vince's chief rivals back in the day.
他们中还有人活着吗
Are any of them still alive?
迈克尔·卡卡诺
Michael Carcano.
他那时是家族的头目  现在也还是
He was head of the family then. He still is today.
我来只是出于对文森·比安奇的尊重
I'm only here out of respect for Vince Bianchi.
我还是1978年的那句话
And I'll say now what I said in '78.
我没有杀他
It wasn't me who did him.
是吗  我们在你的工程下发现了他
Really? Because we found him under your concrete.
什么  我会在自己后院埋尸体吗
What, I'm gonna bury a body in my own backyard?
此外我要是想让人消失  那人就不会被发现
Plus, if I had someone disappear, they'd stay that way.
的确如此  如果不是有开发商
Well, he did... until a developer
要拆掉那栋楼也不会有人发现
decided to tear down that building.
我们知道你想侵占文森的领地
We know that you wanted in on Vince's territory.
有件事你并不清楚
Well, here's something you don't know.
我们那时候正在协商合并的事
Me and him were in talks to merge the families.
这样对双方都有好处
It was a beneficial deal for both sides.
合并失败会影响生意
Losing that merger was bad for business,
为什么我要灭了他呢
so why should I want to get rid of him?
也许是因为你想独吞好处
Maybe because you wanted the whole pie
而不是和人分一杯羹
instead of just a bigger slice.
如果你们还有什么问题
If you boys have any more questions,
跟我的律师去说
talk to my attorney.
要知道过去这么久  是很难找到真相的
You know, after this long, the truth is hard to find.
我要是你们  就不找了
If I was you, I'd quit looking for it.
有时候过去的事情就该让它过去
Sometimes what's in the past should stay there.
你这是威胁吗
Is that a threat?
你觉得呢
What do you think?
我这身衣服太蠢了
I look ridiculous!
蠢得性感
Ridiculously hot.
况且  如果能查出
Besides, what's a little humiliation
是谁杀了文森·比安奇  这点屈辱算什么
when you can find out who killed Vince Bianchi?
好了  文森在哪
All right, so, where is Vince?
他在这里
He's in here.
但愿蕾妮能演好她的部分
Just hope Lanie did her part.
她演得很好
Oh, she did her part, all right.
亲爱的  转个圈  让我看看你的翘臀
Honey, spin around. Show me that caboose.
你就做梦吧  老先生
You keep dreaming, mister.
她穿的是什么
What is she wearing?
我是让她穿成70年代  不是帕姆·格莱尔
I said '70s, not Pam Grier.
她唯一一件70年代的衣服
The only '70s outfit she had
是万圣节的骚狐狸布朗的装束
was her "Foxy Brown" Halloween costume.
来吧  宝贝
Come on, baby.
上过一次白人  就欲罢不能了
Once you go white, nothing else seems right.
我宁愿死也不上你的床  老混蛋
I'd rather be dead than end up in your bed, jive turkey.
好了  别再说了
Okay, that's enough.
-帕里什医生  -她还是个医生
- Dr. Parish. - She's a doctor, too.
这么说她肯定知道...
Whoa, that means she sure knows her way around...
怎样
Well?
哈罗德
Harold?
我们已经履行了我们的承诺
We kept our end of the bargain.
他身上还有什么别的东西吗
Was there anything else on him?
他的东西
Any of his stuff?
一枚尾戒  一块手表
A pinkie ring, a watch...
还有这个
And this.
这是康尼岛上的那种硬币
It's one of those pressed pennies from Coney Island.
你说过会告诉我们的
You said that you'd talk to us.
文森总是带着那玩意以求好运
Vince always carried that coin for luck.
现在看见他  我也说不清楚
Seeing him there... I don't know.
我突然意识到他是真的死了
It just hit me that he's really gone.
哈罗德  我们知道这很难
Harold, we know this is hard.
我们需要你帮忙将杀死文森的凶手绳之以法
We need you to help us bring Vince's killer to justice.
趴下  趴下
Get down! Get down!
好的  谢了
Okay. Thanks.
刚才发生的是真的吗
Did this really just happen?
在我停尸房里的黑帮袭击
An attempted mob hit in my morgue?
蕾妮  这次没人受伤纯粹是运气好
Lanie, it was pure luck that no one got hurt.
哈罗德怎么样了
How's Harold?
卡塞尔送他回家了
Castle took him home.
我们已经派警察保护他了
We've got him under police protection.
贝克特  我听说了发生的事
Yo, Beckett. I heard what happ-- whoa.
什么也别说
Don't you say another word.
看来是职业枪手
Hey. Looks like our shooter was a pro.
他从楼梯跑了  而且把门闩上了
He left by the stairs, and he barred the door.
他早就做好了逃跑准备
He had an exit plan.
有目击者吗
Any witnesses see him?
有  但是他戴着口罩
Yeah, but he was wearing that mask,
所以没人看清他的脸
So no one got a good look at his face,
不过他可能是迈克尔·卡卡诺派来的
But he might have been sent by Michael Carcano.
卡卡诺刚刚警告我和哈维不要插手这案子  对吧
Carcano just warned me and Javi off the case. Right, Javi?
抱歉  你说什么
I'm sorry. What?
查查大楼外的监控录像
Check the security cameras outside the building.
如果我们能确认枪手的身份
If we can I.D. the shooter,
或许我们就能把他和卡卡诺
maybe we can tie him to Carcano
或者真正的幕后主使联系起来
or whoever else was behind this.
衣服不错
Nice dress.
托瑞  有什么发现
Hey, Tory. What do you got?
我在看停尸房周围的交通录像发现了这个
I was checking traffic cam footage near the morgue and found this.
这就是枪手
Here's our shooter.
在半个街区之外
It's half a block away.
他一定是从停尸房的后门出来的
He must have come out the rear exit of the morgue.
看  他摘掉了口罩
Now watch. He takes off his mask.
把这张照片发给有组织犯罪调查科
Send this image to Organized Crime.
或许他们能认出他
Maybe they can I.D. him.
有组织犯罪调查科里没人能认出他来
So, nobody in Organized Crime could tell us who he is?
是的  你看看他
No, but look at him.
他和文森是同一代的人
He's from the same generation as Vince.
或许他参与了一开始的那个案子
Maybe he was even involved in the original hit.
无论怎样  有组织犯罪调查科
Either way, Organized Crime
说枪手可能是从外地来的
said that our shooter might've been brought from out of town
这样我们就没法把他跟雇他的人联系起来了
so that he couldn't be linked back to whoever hired him.
我们把照片发了出去  也发了全境通告
We're circulating the photo, and we already got an APB.
让联调局也查查
Let's run it past FBI, too.
如果他是从外地来的  或许他们能认识他
If he's from out of town, maybe they'll recognize him.
已经做了  但是我们现在需要的
We're already on it, but what we really need
是让哈罗德告诉我们他所知道的
is for your boy Harold to tell us what he knows.
我刚才就是个活靶子
I was like a sitting duck in there.
你怎么能让这种事发生
How could you let this happen?
你算个什么警察
What kind of a cop are you, anyway?
哈罗德  我们正在尽力抓捕那个枪手
Harold, we're doing everything we can to bring in the gunman.
这就是我当告密者的下场
This is what I get for being a snitch.
准确来说  你不是个泄密者
Well, technically, you're not a snitch
因为你目前还什么都没告诉我们
because you haven't actually told us anything yet.
但是他们又不知道
Well, they don't know that.
是的  他们不知道
No. They don't.
他们认为你全都交代了
They figure you're singing like a canary.
你是想让我感觉好一些吗
Are you trying to make me feel better?
你所说的可一点没用
Because this is not helping!
我是想让你明白你把实情说出来
I'm trying to show you you've got nothing to lose
对你有益无害
and everything to gain by coming clean.
告诉我们幕后主使是谁
Tell us who's behind this,
我们可以去抓那人  确保你的安全
We can go after them and keep you safe!
好吧
All right.
我会告诉你们我所知道的一切
I'll tell you everything I know.
我们去警局正式录份口供
Let's go down to the precinct and make it official.
-警局  -是的
- Precinct? - Yeah.
警局
The precinct.
我看到周围有警察会觉得安全一些
I'm -- I'm gonna feel a little safer with all those cops around.
为什么不能在这里说呢
Well, why can't we do it here?
为什么不能在那里说呢
Why can't we do it there?
我告诉你为什么不行
I will tell you why not.
因为一旦哈罗德来到这里
Because the second Harold sets foot in this place,
他的70年代幻想就会破灭
it will burst his little 70's bubble.
如果这里也像70年代一样就行了
It won't burst his bubble if it...looks like the 70's.
你不会是说我们要重新装饰警局吧
You cannot be suggesting that we redecorate the precinct.
这里的框架还是可以的
The bare bones of this place will totally work.
我们只需要把电脑搬走
We just need to take away the computers
然后放上打字机
and put back the typewriters.
不  不行  绝对不行
No! No, absolutely not.
有人想杀死哈罗德
People tried to kill Harold
因为他知道是谁谋杀了文森
because he knows who murdered Vince.
这是让他开口的唯一方法
This is the only way we can get him to talk to us.
他是我们的唯一线索
He's the only lead we have.
盖茨警监绝对不会同意的
Captain Gates will never go for it.
盖茨警监现在不在  你是老大
Captain Gates isn't here. You're in charge.
那其他的警察怎么办
And what about all the other cops?
他们的警服就会露馅
Their clothes are a dead giveaway.
不会的  假如你以上级的身份
Not if you, as ranking officer,
命令他们穿成70年代的样子来上班
order them to come to work dressed in 1970s clothing.
-什么  -我已经在服装店开好账户了
- What?! - I have opened an account at a costume shop --
价格可不便宜
At no small expense.
他们会提供70年代的警察制服
They're gonna help us in our little endeavour
来帮助我们实现这个计划
by providing 1970s police uniforms.
卡塞尔
Castle --
也不算太麻烦
This will be a minor disruption.
我们只需把哈罗德要经过的办公室
We redress the squad room just long enough
重新装饰  让他感觉到70年代的气氛
to walk Harold through, let him dig on that '70s vibe,
然后他就会给我们录口供了
and then he gives us a statement.
成功过一次  这次也会的
It worked before, it'll work again.
太平间只是一个房间而已
The morgue was one room.
你现在说的可是整体70年代化改造
You're talking about an entire '70s makeover.
这可是个大工程
That is a massive undertaking.
这也是我为什么找了个专家  算是吧
Which is why I've called a specialist...of sorts.
-不会吧  -正是
- No. - Yes.
我母亲会帮我们协调...
My mother is gonna come help us coordinate --
你这么做是为了你母亲
You're doing this for your mother?
不  当然不是了
No! Of course not.
有一点吧  是的
A little bit. Yes.
我们的确说过要给她点事做的
Well, we did say we'd give her a project.
是啊  和我们婚礼有关的
Yeah, for our wedding!
而不是我的警局
Not for my precinct!
面对现实吧
Let's face it.
我们不能让那个女人再插手我们的婚礼了
We cannot let that woman anywhere near our wedding.
但是  她会喜欢这差事的
But she will love this,
我们也会因此解决
and then we get to solve
迪斯科年代的最大迷案
the greatest mystery of the disco era,
除了迪斯科流行的原因
besides the popularity of disco itself.
双赢呢
It's a win-win.
我很怀疑
I highly doubt that.
但我也想不出更好的办法了
But I don't see a better option.
你做了正确的选择
You are so doing the right thing,
相信我  你会感谢我的
and trust me, you will thank me.
好好看一眼四周吧
Now, take a good look around...
做一个深情的告别
Bid a fond farewell,
因为等到了明天  这里就是70年代了
because by tomorrow, it'll be the '70s.
怎么要这么久
Hey, what is taking so long down there?
哈罗德准备好出发了
Harold is ready to go,
我快没借口拖住他了
and I'm running out of excuses.
这里简直一团糟
This is a total fiasco.
你是说我老妈吗
A fiasco named Martha Rodgers?
她把这事弄得声势浩大
She's turned this into a huge production.
她甚至叫了演员过来
She's even brought in actors.
什么
She what?!
你能  你能叫她听电话吗
Would -- would you put her on, please?
好  玛莎
Yeah. Uh, Martha?
卡塞尔的电话
Hey. Castle.
-理查德  -是的
- Richard? - Yeah.
喂  亲爱的
Hi, darling.
叫演员做什么  老妈
Actors, mother?
考虑到你那里的人没什么表演天赋
In light of the abysmal talent pool you have here,
所以我雇了一些演员
yes, I've hired a few actors.
除此之外
And not only that,
我还写了一些台词
I have written these scripts
这样大家就知道他们在演什么角色了
so that everybody knows exactly what they're playing.
我们不需要台词
We don't need scripts.
也不需要找人来扮演警察
And we don't need actors to play cops.
我们自己就是警察
We have actual cops!
你这么说真是无知
That is such an ignorant thing to say
简直就是对演艺事业的侮辱
and an insult to the craft of acting.
老妈  我们只要带哈罗德穿过警局
Mother, all we need is to walk Harold through the precinct
进入审讯室就行
and into interrogation.
理查德  我只想给你们做出真实的体验
Richard, I am trying to create an authentic experience here
这样你俩就能专心破案了
so that the two of you can crack this case.
这有什么错吗
Now, is that so wrong?
好了  队长  我们出发吧
Okay, captain, let's get this show on the road.
你听到了吗  老妈
Did you hear that, mother?
音乐起
Music to my ears.
大伙儿听好了  各就各位
All right, everyone! Places, please!
第十二分局  出发吧
12th precinct. Let's boogie.
快出发吧  等不及了
Come on. Let's go already.
太好了  这和我想的一模一样
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah. This is more like it.
我们的小美女来了
Ah, there's the little lady.
靓妹  你看起来...
Hey, sweet cheeks, you look --
少废话  往前走
Stop talking, start walking.
卡塞尔
Castle.
如果没成功  我会杀了你
If this doesn't work, I'm gonna kill you.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
怎么会不成功
It has to work.
看看这地方  棒极了
Look at this place. It's amazing!
承认吧
And admit it,
你也有点享受吧
you're having a little bit of fun.
这些人我基本都认识
Hey, most of these guys I know.
不过这个老家伙是谁
But who are the old farts?
哈罗德  我们该去...
Uh, Harold, we should --
那是西托和莱恩吗
Whoa. Is that Sito and Ryan?
真不敢相信被你说服穿成这样
Can't believe you talked me into this.
演好你的角色  我很投入  你也是
Just play the part, man. I am, you should, too.
斯努基·沃兹和雷·普莱斯
Snookie Watts and Ray Price.
正是我俩  有什么事吗
Oh, yeah, that's us, baby. What it is?
你们就是警界传奇
Oh, you guys are legends.
我在报上见过你们的照片
I seen your picture in the papers.
哈罗德  我们去录口供怎么样
Hey, Harold, what do you say we go take that statement?
我想斯努基和雷帮我录
I want Snookie and Ray to do it.
我爱死这俩人了
I love these guys.
好吧
Okay, fine.
斯努基  雷  带哈罗德去审讯
Snookie, Ray, take harold to interrogation.
你说什么审讯
What do you mean "Interrogation"?
我就是和他俩聊聊天
I'm just gonna talk to these people.
我又没犯罪
I'm no criminal.
真不敢相信你们让这妞指手画脚的
I can't believe you let this chick boss you around.
他从那里看以看到整个房间
He can see the entire bullpen from there.
原计划没那么长
The charade was only supposed to last long enough
只到他进审讯室就结束
to get him to interrogation.
哈罗德会发现这一切都是假的
Harold's gonna realize that this is all fake!
-我们该怎么办  -理查德
-What do we do now? - Richard.
台词在你的桌子上
Scripts are on your desks.
真是过分  警官
This is outrageous, officer!
我的行为完全没有问题
My behavior was entirely consensual!
阿丽克西斯  你在这里做什么
Alexis? What are you doing here?
奶奶叫我过来
Gram asked me to come.
扮演一个离家出走的少女
I'm playing a teenage runaway
搭顺风车去纽约
who hitchhiked her way to the big apple
追寻她的梦想
in search of her dreams.
穿成这样
Wearing that?
吊带背心70年代可流行了
Halter tops are big in the '70s.
村姑衫也是啊
So were those peasant blouses.
你为什么不穿那个呢
Why -- why didn't you wear one of those?
我们还真有台词
We really do have scripts.
是啊  可斯努基和雷没有
Yeah, but Snookie and Ray don't.
我得跟你们说
I got to tell you,
我太喜欢你们治理街区的法子
I dig how you guys clean up the streets.
多谢支持  哈罗德
Yeah, well, that's, um, super groovy, Harold,
但我们还是说说文森  是谁杀了他
but how about we talk about Vince and who killed him?
首先
First...
你们抓的那男的是怎么回事
what is the scoop on that guy you busted?
就那个裸着的波多黎各男妓
That naked Puerto Rican cat?
到底怎么回事啊
What really happened there, huh?
裸着的波多黎各男妓么
The naked Puerto Rican cat?
那个
Uh, that, um...
这类人我们抓的太多了
We busted so many naked Puerto Rican cats that, um...
好吧  哈罗德  跟你说实话吧
All right, Harold. Here's the low down, brother.
是啊  我和斯努基
Yeah, yeah, sure, me and Snookie,
我们坐着红箭满城巡查
We book around town in the red rocket
四处抓恶人  猎美人
busting bad guys and hunting stone-cold foxes,
但你是解决文森·比安奇谋杀案的关键
but you are gonna solve the murder of Vince Bianchi,
这比我们做过的事
and that is something more righteous
要正义得多
than we have ever done.
我们只想听听你的故事
Now, what we want is to hear your story.
你能说说吗
Can you dig it?
"给我坐下  雷诺"
"Have a seat, Reno."
我本来就坐着
I'm already seated.
抱歉
Sorry, that's...
我不跟小白脸说话  蠢货
I don't talk to no fuzz...pig.
那你得跟这个蠢货开口
Well, you're gonna talk to this pig.
是...是这个小白脸
This -- this fuzz.
是吗  凭啥啊  大话精
Yeah? Why's that, jive turkey?
因为我会奉上一份火辣劲爆的认罪协议
Because I'm about to make you one sweet-ass deal.
我了个天  这谁写的
My god, who wrote this?
我写的
I did.
我做不到
I can't do it.
我就是戒不掉  你懂吗
I can't give up my connection, you dig?
我要你告诉我是谁卖给你的毒品  现在就说
I want the name of your pusher, and I want it now!
好吧
Okay.
那我说
Here it is.
我全说
Everything I know.
我和文森  我们本来要碰头的
Uh, me and Vince, we were gonna meet up...
就那天晚些时候
later that night.
但他一直没来  我就知道出事了
When I didn't hear from him, I knew something was wrong.
而你知道谁是幕后黑手
And you knew who was behind it.
但为了把事情说清楚
But, to get the whole picture,
我得先说说名流
we got to talk about Glitterati.
那个  名流是个什么
Okay, yeah, what's -- what's -- what's Glitterati?
就那个俱乐部  你知道的
The nightclub, you know.
对  我知道
Yeah, yeah, I know.
什么声音
What is that sound?
我不知道  什么声音
Uh, I don't know. What is that? What...
哈罗德  你刚要跟我们说名流的事
Yeah, Harold, uh, you were telling us about Glitterati.
没错  就那家俱乐部
Yeah, that -- that's a nightclub, yes.
我们知道
We know that,
但这跟杀文森的凶手有什么关系
but what does it have to do with who killed Vince?
我不知道
I don't know.
什么意思  哈罗德
W-what do you mean, Harold?
你刚才正要告诉我们呢
Uh, you were just about to tell us.
快说吧  哥们
Come on, lay it on me, brother.
是啊  我正要说
Yeah, I just had it.
名流
The Glitterati.
名流就是
Glitterati is the --
是这一切的关键
It's the key to this whole thing.
我想不起来了
I can't remember.
他马上就要说出文森被杀的重要信息了
He was this close to giving up the deets on Vince's death,
但某位仁兄的手机响了  把他脑子搅乱了
but then somebody's cellphone rang and he lost his mojo.
那就帮他想起来啊
Then help him get it back.
我们试过了  但他只记得
We tried, but all he can remember
这事跟一家名为名流的俱乐部有关
is it had something to do with a club called Glitterati.
我建议我和埃斯波带他去看看
I say me and Espo take him there,
也许能让他想起来
maybe it'll jog his memory.
这都过去三十多年了
That was over 30 years ago.
那地方没准都拆掉了
That place probably doesn't even exist anymore.
尽管那地方改建过不少次
Actually, it's been through a lot of incarnations,
但你猜怎么着  又改回70年代的俱乐部了
but guess what -- it's back to being a '70s club again.
没准管用呢
This could work.
先是太平间
First the morgue,
紧接着是整个分局
then the precinct,
现在你们又想带他去怀旧夜店
and now you guys want to take him to a club?
不行  绝对不行  就此打住
No. No. This has to stop.
我们费了这么大劲  眼看就成了
After everything we've already do-- unh-unh. We're too close.
现在停手的话  我们就白费力气了
We stop now, we walk away with nothing.
贝克特探长  这是作什么妖呢
Detective Beckett! What the hell is going on here?!
带他去名流  快走
Take him to Glitterati. Go! Go!
你是不是说过我会感谢你
Didn't you say I'd be thanking you?
大概没到时候吧  盖茨警监
Maybe just not right away. Captain Gates.
我还以为你去参加反恐研讨...
I thought you were at a, uh, terrorism sem--
因为有炸弹威胁就取消了
It was cancelled due to a bomb threat.
真是太讽刺
Which is ironic.
卡塞尔先生  你脑子出了什么毛病
Mr. Castle, what on earth possessed you
想把我的分局变成老侦探剧片场
to turn my precinct into the set of "Kojak"?!
对了  我是不是该称呼您  卡塞尔队长
Oh, or should I address you as...Captain Castle?
那可不是我的主意
Okay, that was so not my idea.
是吗  那其他都是你的主意吧
Oh, but the rest of this was?
长官  公平地讲
Sir. In fairness --
还有你  贝克特探长
And you, Detective Beckett,
你知道这案子关注度有多高
you know what a high-profile case this is.
你怎么能让他这么胡来
How could you allow this circus?
长官  考虑到他对70年代的痴迷
Sir, given his fixation with the '70s,
我们以为这样有可能使哈罗德·利昂
we figured that this would be an opportunity
把他知道的关于文森特·比安奇谋杀案的一切
to let Harold Leone open up about his knowledge
都告诉我们
on Vincent Bianchi's murder.
他说了吗
And did he?
这个
Well...
还没说  但是
no, but --
这么说来  你们搞了这么一出闹剧
So, all this mess, this ridiculous display...
却一点成果都没有
and you have nothing to show for it?
我们有成果
Actually, sir, we do.
太平间枪案的通缉嫌犯有消息了
A.P.B. just snagged our suspect from the morgue shooting.
他在泽西高速的一处收费站被截
He stopped at a tollbooth on the Jersey Turnpike.
他们正把他抓捕归案
They're bringing him in now.
正经的刑侦办法才能取得突破
A breakthrough achieved by proper police work,
不是搞什么时空穿越
not by pretending it's the '70s!
趁我现在还没想好怎么罚你们
Until I can decide what disciplinary action to take,
你俩赶紧从我眼前消失
I want the both of you out of my sight,
尤其是你
especially you.
我叫埃斯波西托和莱恩来
I'm bringing in Esposito and Ryan.
长官  他俩都不在
Sir... they're not here.
他们带着哈罗德去场子了
They took Harold to a -- a disco.
我跟你说  就这行头  这座驾
I tell you, these clothes, that car,
我感觉势不可挡
I feel invincible, man.
就像雷·普莱斯一样
Like Ray Price.
酷的掉渣  还顶着70年代的名字
Kicking ass and taking names '70s style.
现在我懂了
I get it now, baby.
你懂了就好
Yeah, good for you.
这简直太棒了
Wow, this is out of sight!
你想起来什么没  哈罗德
Anything coming back to you there, Harold? Huh?
关于名流和文森谋杀案的关系
Yeah, about how Glitterati connects back to Vince.
没有  还没有  再等等
Uh, no, no. No, not yet. Not yet.
给我点时间  给我...
Give me a minute. Give me a...
你好啊
Hey.
宝贝  宝贝
Oh, baby, baby!
怎么样  美女
How you doing, hot stuff?
裙子不错  能脱下来吗
That's a nice dress. Can I talk you out of it?
你们是在搞化装舞会吗
You throwing a costume party out there?
这是你试图在太平间
Well, here's you in your costume
杀死哈罗德·利昂的装束
after you tried to kill Harold Leone at the morgue.
不过是一个人在路上走
That's a guy walking down the street.
我只看到了这个
That's all I see.
没错  但你看来常去案发现场
Yeah, well, you seem to be walking down a lot of streets
周边散步  让我们来看看
where homicides happen. Let's see.
罗伯特·德克尔
Robert Decker,
斗殴  杀人
assault convictions, manslaughter,
六起买凶杀人案的嫌疑犯
a person of interest in six contract killings.
你手里没有任何证据
Look, you got no proof.
没有人能证明我在那里
No witnesses can say I was there.
包括你
Including you.
我们在你的车门里
We found your gun
找到了藏着的枪
hidden in the door panel of your car.
相信里面的子弹会和太平间枪案的一样
It's gonna match the bullets fired in the Morgue.
我抓到你了
I've got you.
现在  为什么不告诉我是谁雇了你
Now, why don't you tell me who hired you?
我会在检察官前说你几句好话
I'll put in a good word with the D.A.
招了吧  谁雇的你
Come on. Who hired you?
是迈克尔·卡卡诺吗
Was it Michael Carcano?
无可奉告
I got nothing to say.
你多大  六十了吧
What are you, like 60 years old?
就算判个十年  对你来说也是终身监禁
So, even another 10 years is gonna be life in prison for you.
我在牢里的朋友
I got more friends on the inside
可比在牢外的多
than the outside at this point.
你们这儿的人真是配合默契啊
You guys run a real tight ship here.
卡塞尔  搞什么
Castle... what the hell?
我有发现
I got something.
我在找70年代在名流拍摄的老照片
I was looking at old photos taken at Glitterati in the '70s.
结果发现了三张文森
I found three of Vince
在舞池里尽情摇摆的照片
on the dance floor boogying his heart out.
好吧  文森去夜店玩了  这有什么稀奇
Okay, so Vince went to the club. How is that news?
因为这些照片是在不同场合拍的
Because these pictures are taken on three different occasions,
而他总是穿着一样的衣服
and he's always wearing the same thing.
灰蓝色西装
The powder-blue suit.
这是个特定的迪斯科装束
It's a designated disco outfit.
文森一定在被杀当晚去了名流
Vince must've gone to Glitterati the night that he was killed.
或许他就在那里被杀的
It might even be where he was killed,
看看这家俱乐部的老板是谁
because look who owns the club.
请等一下  贝克特
Excuse me one second. Beckett.
哈罗德在哪儿
Where's Harold?
-他刚去上厕所了  -找到他
- He just took off for a second to take a leak.  - Find him.
弗兰克·鲁索以前是这家俱乐部的老板  现在也是
Frank Russo owned the club back then, and he owns it now.
明白
Got it.
抱歉  哥们
Hey, sorry, buddy.
你要是想见鲁索先生  得先预约才行
You want to see Mr. Russo, you need to make an appointment.
没关系
Oh, no sweat.
是谁...  哈罗德
Who the -- Harol-- Harold?
承认你杀了文森吧
Admit you killed Vince.
乖乖承认吧  我让你死个痛快
Just admit it to me, and you won't suffer.
哈罗德
Harold!
放下武器  哈罗德
Drop the weapon, Harold!
马上发现
Drop it now!
我的东西在哪儿
Where is my stuff?
警官把我口袋都掏空了
The booking officer made me empty my pockets.
你现在的问题要比你的个人物品严重的多  哈罗德
You have bigger problems than your personal effects, Harold,
比如非法袭击  比如欺骗警察
Like assault charges, like lying to the police.
告诉我
Tell me something.
现在是哪一年
What year is it?
别...
Don't --
别装了  哈罗德
Drop the act, Harold.
告诉我今年是哪一年
Tell me what year it is.
-我知道你很清楚  -求你了  别问了
- I know that you know. - Please stop. Please.
到底是哪一年  哈罗德
What year is it, Harold?
我希望现在就是那一年  可以吗
It is the year I need it to be, okay?
那时候文森还活着  一切都很美好
When Vince was alive and things were good.
哈罗德  你为什么认为是弗兰克·鲁索杀了文森
Harold, what makes you think Frank Russo killed Vince?
文森只有去名流才穿那件蓝西装
Vince only ever wore that blue suit to Glitterati.
当你们说他死时穿着那件  我就知道了
When you two said that's what he had on, I knew.
关于那晚发生的事  你还记得多少
What else do you remember about what happened that night?
在我们去吃晚饭之前
Before we went to dinner,
文森跟我说晚点要见我
Vince told me that he needed to meet up with me later,
他有很重要的事情要说
that he had something important to tell me.
然后他迟迟没有露面  我很担心
And then when he didn't show up, I got worried.
我开着车到处去找
I...I was driving all over the place looking for him,
我去了他所有经常去的地方  我甚至去了名流
I-I hit all of his old haunts. I even went to Glitterati.
但门上贴了个告示
But there was a sign on the door
写着因私事关闭
that said it was closed for a private event.
而当你听说文森穿着那件西装
And when you heard Vince had that suit on?
我想那私事就是弗兰克杀害了他
I figured the private event was Frank killing him.
但我知道我不能直接去找他算账
But I knew I couldn't just go straight at Frank,
特别是在他要干掉我之后
not after he tried to whack me.
你就一直耍我们
You were playing us the whole time.
不  不  一开始并没有
No, no. Not at the beginning.
但那天有人朝我开枪  我的记忆就回来了
But when I got shot at... that's when things got real.
就像是  突然明白了过来
It was like, uh -- like a bubble popped inside me.
你让我们带你去警局
You asked us to bring you to the precinct
就是想知道弗兰克现在长什么样子
hoping you could see what Frank looks like now,
希望我们能直接把你送到他门前
hoping we would lead you right to his doorstep.
弗兰克要为他对文森做的事付出代价
Frank needed to pay for what he did to Vince.
我没有想要干掉任何人  包括文森和哈罗德
I didn't try to whack anybody -- Not Vince, Not Harold, either.
那是谁干的  弗兰克
Then who did, Frank?
我怎么知道
How the hell would I know?
但如果哈罗德说是我杀的文森
But if Harold is saying that I took out Vince,
那真是大错特错
he is way off base.
文森那晚去了名流
Well, Vince went to Glitterati that night,
而你却正好因为私事停业
yet you had it closed for an event.
这是你的俱乐部  弗兰克
It's your club, Frank.
你是要告诉我
Are you trying to tell us that
你不知道你自己的俱乐部里发生了什么吗
you don't know what's going on inside your own club?
那晚到底发生了什么
What happened that night?
我从未跟别人说过这件事
What I'm about to tell you, I never told anybody.
是文森
It was Vince.
文森才是那晚包下了俱乐部的人
Vince booked the club that night.
文森有私事吗
Vince had the private event?
他在晚饭时跟我提出来
He brought it up to me over dinner,
说要把俱乐部整晚都包下来
said he wanted the club to himself that night.
他是老大  我能拒绝吗
I mean, he was the boss. What was I gonna do, say no?
文森去了我的俱乐部  结果失踪了
Vince goes to my club, ends up missing.
如果人们知道的话  他们就会以为是我杀了他的
If people knew that, they would've thought I killed him,
所以我从没说过这件事
So I kept my mouth shut about it.
文森为什么要包下俱乐部
Why would Vince want the club?
他一直在说要收心  要结婚
He had been talking about settling down, getting married.
我猜他是要跟某个姑娘求婚
I figured he was proposing to some girl.
再加上  第二天早上我去开门的时候
Plus, when I opened up the next morning,
《最后一舞》的碟就放在转盘上
"Last dance" was on the turntable.
那时候最浪漫的歌曲
A romantic favorite back then.
哪个姑娘
So, what girl?
他从没提起过  我也没问
He didn't talk about her, and I didn't ask.
但我知道有这么个人对他很重要
But I knew he had someone special in his life.
那个神秘的女人是谁
Who's this mystery woman?
是她引诱文森到俱乐部杀了他
Did she lure Vince to the club to be assassinated,
还是他的浪漫计划出了大纰漏
or...some romantic plan of his go horribly awry?
可能就是这么一回事
That may be exactly what happened.
我翻看了哈罗德的个人物品
I went through Harold's personal effects.
看我找到了什么
Look at what I found.
你担心的是这个吗  哈罗德
Was this the item that you were so worried about, Harold?
康尼岛的  和文森的一模一样
It's from Coney Island. Just like Vince's.
连敲在后面的日期也一样
Even has the same date stamped on it.
你也和文森一样  随身携带
You carried it with you just like Vince did.
你在太平间里一看到它就红了眼睛
Seeing it at the morgue brought you to tears.
你和文森是爱人
You and Vince were in love.
没错
Yes.
我们是爱人
We were.
我们也尝试过不去爱  可...
We tried not to be, but...
而你就要失去他了
And you were going to lose him.
等等
Wait.
你不会以为是我杀了文森吧
You can't be thinking that I killed Vince.
没错  我们相信他是去名流
Yeah, we believe that he went to Glitterati
求婚的
to propose marriage.
他为了一个女人要离开你
He was leaving you for a woman.
那是当然
Of course he was.
叫他结婚的人是我
I was the one who told him he had to get married.
如果有人发现我们的关系  那会毁了他
It would ruin him if people found out about us.
能做他背后的人...
Being his number two...
我就很满足了
was enough for me.
哈罗德
Harold?
如果文森要结婚
If Vince was getting married,
怎么可能没人知道呢
how come no one else knew about it?
这是一个秘密
It had to be kept hush-hush.
这不仅仅是一桩婚事
You see, this was more than a marriage.
也是一次合并
It was a merger.
文森要娶的是迈克尔·卡卡诺的妹妹
Vince was gonna marry Michael Carcano's sister
两家合为一家
and unite the two families.
但他从没告诉过我  他要在那晚求婚
But he never told me that he was gonna propose that night.
迈克尔·卡卡诺的妹妹是谁  她叫什么名字
Who is Michael Carcano's sister? What's her name?
弗兰克不在
Frank's not here.
没事  其实我们找的不是弗兰克·鲁索夫人
Yeah, actually, we're not looking for Frank, Mrs. Russo.
我们能进来吗
Would you mind if we came in?
长话短说吧
Let's keep this short.
我的冥想老师就快到了
My meditation teacher's on her way.
好吧  你来说说
Okay, so then why don't you tell us
文森消失那晚  名流到底发生了什么
what happened at Glitterati the night that Vince vanished?
-我怎么会知道  -因为你在场
- How would I know? - Because you were there.
你说什么
What are you talking about?
文森放了那首《最后一舞》
Vince had "Last dance" playing.
你以为他就要求婚了
You thought he was going to propose,
为了巩固
to cement, as it were,
你们两家的关系
the union between your two families.
但他却无法向你求婚
But he couldn't go through with it.
你接受不了拒绝
You couldn't handle the rejection.
于是  等他转身  你朝他开了枪
So, as he left, you shot him in the back,
然后正脸又是一枪
then again in the face.
因为这是个人恩怨
You know, because it was personal.
你们的想法真是天马行空
You guys have quite the imagination.
你哥哥知道文森的死会引发黑帮大战
Your brother knew that Vince's murder would trigger a mob war,
于是他利用混凝土之便
So he used his access to concrete
让文森消失
to make Vince disappear.
之后  你又勾搭上了弗兰克
After that, you hitched your wagon to Frank,
但是他在比安奇家族的地位实在是...
but his tenure as head of the Bianchi family was...
微乎其微
disappointingly brief.
你们什么都证明不了
You can't prove any of this.
只不过是个推论  你们可以走了
All you've got is a story. Now get out.
如果只是推论
If it is just a story,
那你也不会雇一个杀手
then you wouldn't have hired a hit man.
罗伯特·德克尔不想死在监狱里
Robert Decker decided that he didn't want to die in prison,
他供出了你
so he rolled on you.
他告诉我们  当你发现哈罗德配合警方后
He told us that you paid him to kill Harold
是你雇他杀了哈罗德
when you found out he was talking to the cops.
而有趣的是
And here's the funny part.
也许对你来说很无趣
Well, maybe not so funny to you.
没有人  包括哈罗德知道你杀了文森
Nobody, including Harold, knew you killed Vince.
如果你不去追杀哈罗德
If you had just left Harold alone,
事情也许就算过去了
it would've stayed that way.
玛丽亚·鲁索
Maria Russo...
你因涉嫌谋杀被逮捕
you are under arrest for conspiracy to commit murder.
我们走
Let's go.
真希望文森答应了他们的婚事
I wish Vince had just said yes to her.
这样也许他还活着
Maybe then he'd still be alive.
但至少他遵从了自己的心
Well, he had to follow his heart.
这也许是他那晚想告诉你的
It's probably what he wanted to tell you that night.
知道他为我付出的真相  真有那么重要吗
Isn't that something, knowing he did that for me?
在21世纪的感觉如何
So, how does it feel to be in the 2010s?
还行吧
Eh, it's okay.
我已经做好准备  告别70年代
I'm ready to say goodbye to the '70s,
告别文森
say goodbye to Vince.
那我们就用70年代的方式来告别吧
Well, then let's do it the right way.
以此纪念随时间逝去的人
Honor the times along with the man.
卡塞尔  别告诉我你...
Castle, tell me you don't mea--
没错
Oh, but I do.
真没想到你还会跳迪斯科
I had no idea you could disco dance!
卡塞尔  我隐藏的天赋多了去呢
Oh, Castle, I'm a woman of many hidden talents.
待我一个一个慢慢发现
I look forward to discovering every single one.
-老爸  -宝贝  我这衣服时髦吧
- Hey, dad. - Oh, sweetie, I'm digging those groovy duds!
她这身打扮是不是美极了
Doesn't she look stunning in this outfit?
这次遮得多了点  我很欣慰
I'm just glad it covers more this time.
老爸
Oh, dad.
我怎么了
I -- what?
老妈
Mother.
非常感谢你做的一切
Thank you so much for everything.
真是太棒了
It was spectacular.
看来你们终于理解我的审美了
Now that you guys have connected to my vision here,
或许我们再去挑挑花
perhaps we can revisit the flowers?
-不  -不要吗
- No. - No?
享受吧
Dig it, man.
70年代还真是挺酷的
The '70s is a cool place to vist,
但我可不想活在70年代
but I would not want to live there, bro.
你确定吗
You sure about that, blood?
老天  行行好
Oh, lord, have mercy!
斯努基  斯努基模式开启
Oh, Snookie, Snookie now. Hey!
盖茨警监
Captain Gates.
是不是说明原谅我们了
Does this mean all is forgiven?
只是说明我喜欢跳舞  卡塞尔先生
It means I like to dance, Mr. Castle.
太好了
Hey. Oh, perfect.
干杯
Cheers.
卡塞尔  看  看哈罗德
Oh, Castle, look. Look at Harold.